ちょっと待て～！ 先っちょが…➡
(新八)ｽﾅｯｸで ｱﾙﾊﾞｲﾄする
ﾎﾞｸの姉 お妙は➡
あれ!? 先っちょが…➡
お妙さ～ん!!
いざ！
(銀時)尋常に！
(２人)勝負!!
そこで ｹﾂ毛ﾎﾞｰﾎﾞｰだという
男に出会った｡
(お妙)ｹﾂ毛ごと 愛します｡
ｹﾂが 毛だるまだったら
どうするよ？
自称 愛のｽﾄｰｶｰと化した
この男を あざむくため➡
(近藤)もし お妙さんの彼氏がさ➡
ねえ～～っ!!
許婚を名乗った銀さんは
決闘を申し込まれる｡
銀さんは ﾋｰﾛｰとは思えない
卑怯な手で 勝ったのだった…｡
My sister, Otae, who works part-time at a snack shop met a man with a furry butt.
If your boyfriend's rear end looked like an afro with a part down the middle, what would you do?
I would love him, butt afro and all.
Otae!
In order to thwart this self-proclaimed Thief of Hearts,
Gin declares that he is engaged to my sister, and ends up being challenged to a duel.
Let's go!
A fair...
...duel!
Hold on a second!
The blade! The t-t-tip!
Gin won with a cowardly trick you could hardly call "heroic".
["Find the Silver-haired Samurai!!" The Shinsengumi are searching all over Edo.]
[Odd Jobs Gin receives a new request... who is this old man?]
(隊士)副長～!!
Vice Chief!
Is it true that the Chief was jilted by some chick?
(隊士)局長が 女にﾌﾗれたうえ…！
(隊士)女を賭けた決闘で 汚い手
使われて負けたって ﾎﾝﾄなのか!?
Not only that, he got tricked into a duel and lost?!
(隊士)女に ﾌﾗれるのは
いつものことだが➡
Getting shot down by the ladies is nothing new for him, but I can't believe he lost a fight!
喧嘩で負けたって
信じらんねえよ！
(隊士)銀髪の侍ってのは
何者なんだよ！
Just who is this silver-haired samurai?!
(土方)会議中に
やかましいんだよ｡
Pipe down, we're in a meeting.
あの 近藤さんが
負けるわけねえだろうが！
And there's no way Kondo would lose.
誰だ？
くだらねえ噂 たれ流してんのは｡
Who the hell's been spreading such baseless rumors?
(隊士)沖田隊長が…!!
(隊士)ｽﾋﾟｰｶｰで ふれ回ってたぜ！
Captain Okita...
...was announcing it over the loudspeaker.
(沖田)ｵﾚは 土方さんに
聞きやした｡
I heard it from you, Hijikata.
ｺｲﾂに しゃべったｵﾚが
ﾊﾞｶだった…｡
What was I thinking, telling that loud mouth?
なんだよ！
結局 ｱﾝﾀが 火種じゃねえか!!
What?! You're the one who started the rumor?!
(隊士)偉そうな顔なさって
ふざけんじゃねえよ!!
So why're you chewing us out? Give us a break!
ってことは なに？
ﾏｼﾞなの!? あの噂!?
What, so it's true then?!
(騒ぎ声)
うるせぇ～～っ!!
Shaaddap!!
(山崎)のわっ…！
会議中に 私語したﾔﾂは 切腹だ｡
ｵﾚが 介錯してやる｡
The next officer who talks about private matters during this meeting commits seppuku.
And I'll assist.
山崎… まず ｵﾒｴからだ｡
Yamazaki, you first.
えぇ～っ!?
ｵﾚ… 何も しゃべって…｡
What? But I didn't say anything.
Methinks thou dost protest too much.
(土方)しゃべってんだろうが
現在進行形で!!
(土方)おりゃ～っ！
(山崎)ひぃ～～っ！ 勘弁…!!
Hey, guys!  Hey, this is a lively meeting for a change.
(近藤)うい～っす！
いつになく 白熱した会議だな！
よし！ じゃあ みんな!!
Right! Okay, everyone...
今日も元気に
市中 見回りにいこうか!!
let's go out there and do our civic duty, shall we?!
ん？ どうしたの？
…はぁ｡
Huh? What's wrong?
["Fighting Should Be Done with Fists"]
Then it's all right?
(隊士)それじゃあ… いいんすね!?
(土方)どうせ 止めたって
やるんだろうが｡
You'll go at it even if I try to stop them.
安心してください 副長！
必ず 見つけ出しますから!!
Don't worry, Chief. We'll find him without fail!
よ～し！ いくぞ!!
(隊士たち)おう!!
All right, let's go!
Right!
わかってねえな…｡
They don't get it.
《近藤さんをやった相手が➡
Do they actually think they can beat someone who challenged Kondo?
お前らごときで
つぶせるとでも思ってんのか？》
(隊士)いいか！ 相手は １人だ!!
Now get this!
It's just one opponent!
(隊士)必ず 見つけ出せ！
真選組の名誉にかけて!!
Find him!
For the honor of the Shinsengumi!
(隊士)ﾀｰｹﾞｯﾄは 銀髪の侍だ！
Our target is...a silver-haired samurai!
おいおい おいおい！
Hey, hey, hey!
まさか ｵﾚを
倒そうってんじゃねえだろうな？
You don't plan on beating me, do you?
それは あれだ…
無謀を通り越して➡
Not only is that reckless, it borders on arrogance, no, insolence.
傲慢どころか 膨満感だよ｡
ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ 出ちゃうって｡
(ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ)
Enough to make me belch.
(神楽)やるなら
命がけで くるｱﾙよ｡ 二度と➡
If you plan on fighting, put your life on the line.
I'll make it so you'll never belch again.
ｹﾞｯﾌﾟのできない体にしてやるｱﾙ！
(ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ)
(新八)ﾌﾝ… 気合いで 勝負が
決まるほど甘くなんてないですよ｡
We're not so lame that we'll succumb to just your fighting spirit.
この勝負 ｹﾞｯﾌﾟなんかじゃなくて➡
This fight isn't about belching, it's about brains.
頭脳が ものをいう｡
(ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ)
(親父)ｹﾞｯﾌﾟなんて
どうでもいいから 早くしろって！
Never mind belching. Just get on with it!
(ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ)
♪♪～
《皆さん こんばんは｡
志村 新八です｡
Good evening, everyone. I'm Shinpachi Shimura.
新緑も 日に日に
色が濃くなってきましたね｡
Everyday, the trees turn greener.
ところで なぜ ﾎﾞｸらが➡
By the way, the reason why we're scowling at each other like this is...
こんな顔して
にらみ合ってるかというと➡
実は
とっても深い事情があるんです》
Well, it's complicated.
《ｵｯｽ！ ｵﾗ 悟空｡ おい みんな！
Yo! I'm Goku!
Hey, everyone! The great space war has begun!
とうとう 宇宙 一大決戦が
始まっちまったぞ！
難しいことは
よくわかんねえけど➡
I don't know about the difficult stuff, but I'm really shocked.
ｵﾗ すげえ ﾋﾞｯｸﾘしたぞ！》
おい お前ら｡ 心の声のﾌﾘして
全部 まる聞こえだぞ｡
Hey, guys.
I can hear you guys thinking out loud!
壊れたﾌﾘですか？ この野郎｡
That's pretty bad acting, numbskulls.
《ほっといてください！
これも 作戦の１つですから！》
Leave us alone. This is strategy!
《壊れたﾌﾘとは 失礼ｱﾙ！
ﾌﾘとは!!》
How rude! Calling it bad acting.
《ただでさえ 子供に伝わりにくい
ｱﾆﾒとか言われてんだ｡
They're saying "this anime is hard for kids to understand".
いいかげんにしねえと
時間枠 移動のうえ➡
Better shape up, or it won't just be moving time slots! We'll be cancelled!"
打ち切られっぞ！ と 銀時は
心の中で叫んでいた…》
So shouted Gintoki in his heart.
《叫んでいた って…｡ 銀さん
ﾏﾈしないでくださいよ！》
Shouted? Gin, don't copy me!
《ﾊﾞｶ野郎！ こんなことで
負けてられっかよ!!》
Dumbass! As if we can lose something like this.
《そうｱﾙ！ この勝負だけは
絶対 負けられないｱﾙ!!》
Right. This is one match we cannot lose.
(親父)どうして こんなことに
なっちまったのか…｡
How'd it turn out like this?
Anyway, take a look at this!
とりあえず これを見ろ！
(親父)いつものように
怠惰な日常を送っていた➡
[The Story So Far]
The Odd Jobs gang - Gintoki, Shinpachi, and Kagura - went about their lives as usual.
銀時 新八 神楽が 万事屋一行｡
その 平穏を打ち破ったのは
１人の依頼人であった｡
But a client shattered the peace.
(親父)その人物こそ➡
He was a carpenter and advisor of the Kabukicho Town Council,
歌舞伎町 町内会 相談役
兼 大工の➡
石田･ﾋﾟｴｰﾙ･源八左右衛門｡
Ishida Pierre Genpachisayuemon.
63歳 乙女座｡
Age: 63. Astrological sign: Virgo.
[Due to Mr. Ishida's ego, this image has been touched up 275%. - Sorry.]
彼の依頼は 大工の手伝い｡
His request was for a carpenter's assistant.
しかし その依頼には➡
However, the request had a frightening catch to it.
恐ろしい罠が
仕掛けられていたのだ｡
そう 人材は １人！
He only wants one person.
たった１人だけが
働くことになるのだ！
Just one of them would work!
[Due to Mr. Ishida's ego, this image has been touched up 384%.]
その瞬間 彼らは動いた！
They reacted instantly.
ﾊｲﾚﾍﾞﾙな駆け引きと攻防｡
口八丁 手八丁｡
A high-level negotiation going back and forth, voices and hands going non-stop.
さまざまな懸案が 提出されては
却下されていく｡
Proposals put forth only to be rejected.
丁々発止の結果➡
[Due to Mr. Ishida's ego, this image has been touched up 40 thousand trillion and 12%.]
When the dust finally settled, they had decided on a method to choose the one.
彼らは その１人を決める
ある方法へと たどりついたのだ｡
[Give us a break, you old fart!]
The method was
その方法とは…
勝負の王道 ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝである！
that greatest of challenges...
Rock, paper, scissors!
いいか 一発勝負！
文句はねえな!!
Ready, one match decides! No whining, right?!
《負ければ １日 重労働｡
この勝負 絶対に負けられない！》
If I lose, I get one day of manual labor!
I will not lose this match!
《どんな手を使ってでも…！》
《必ず 勝つｱﾙ！》
No matter how I do it...
I must win, uh-huh!
それじゃ いくぞ～！ ｼﾞｬ～ﾝ…!!
Let's do it? Ready!
Howacha!
ほあちゃ～～っ!!
ぐはっ…！
Set!
って 何やってんだよ
神楽ちゃん！
What're you doing, Kagura?!
これ ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝだから！ しかも
先出しなんて 聞いたことないし!!
This is Rock, Paper, Scissors!
And what's up with showing your hand early?!
先手必勝ｱﾙよ！
The early hand is victorious!
だから ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝだって
言ってんじゃん!!
I told you, this is Rock, Paper, Scissors!
いいぜ！
ｵﾒｴらが その気だったら➡
All right! If that's how you wanna play, so be it!
こっちも その気で
いかせてもらう!!
おい～っ!! ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝだって
言ってんだろうが～!!
Hey! I said, this is Rock, Paper, Scissors!
いいか？ 一発勝負！
文句はねえな!!
Ready, one match decides! No whining, right?
それじゃ いくぞ～！ 最初は ｸﾞｰ!!
Ready? First is...
Rock.
おいおい どういうつもりだ？
お二人さん？
Hey, what's with you two?
おじさんは たしか
最初は ｸﾞｰ！ って➡
Didn't I just say, rock was first?
言ったはずだよな？
ｳﾁの実家じゃ これ ｸﾞｰいうｱﾙ！
In my family, this is rock.
うわっ 苦しい！
なにそれ？ 言い訳!?
Oh man! What? Excuses?
意味わかんないんですけど～！
I don't know what you're on about.
そういう銀さんも
ﾊﾟｰ 出してますけどね｡
Well, you've got paper too.
あ～いこ～で… しょ！
Again.
Here we go!
Do you even know what Rock, Paper, Scissors is?!
ｱﾝﾀら ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝの意味 知ってんの!?
なんすか!? それ！
What is that?
見て わからないｱﾙか？
ｶﾆｱﾙよ ｶﾆ！
Can't you tell? This is a crab.
少なくとも ｸﾞｰよりは 高級だな｡
It's better than a stone.
しかし このｵﾚ様には
かなうまい！
But you still can't beat mine.
どこの家族 連れてきてんの！
Whose family is that supposed to be?
子供が まだ
食べてるでしょうが！
The kids are still eating.
だから ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝなんだってば～!!
I said this is Rock, Paper, Scissors!
(神楽)新八の 負けｱﾙ｡
しっかり 働いてくるｱﾙよ｡
You lose, Shinpachi. Work hard.
なんで ﾎﾞｸなんだよ！
Huh?! Why me? You both broke the rules, so you lose!
２人の 反則負けだろ!!
ふざけんなよ！
Don't give me that! I'm just using my head! Quit acting like a baby!
こっちは 知恵絞って
ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝやってんだよ!! 甘えんな！
世の中には ﾙｰﾙがあるっての
知ってますか!?
There are rules in the world. Don't you know that?
(神楽)ﾙｰﾙは
破るためにあるｱﾙよ｡
Rules are made to be broken.
ふざけるな～!!
Quit kidding around!
はい 銀さんの勝ち～｡
ｳﾞｨｸﾄﾘｰ｡
Okay, Gin wins.
Victory!
えぇ～～っ!?
Whaaaaat?!
じゃあな 負け犬｡
しっかり働いてこいや｡
Too bad, loser. Work hard.
そうだぞ 新八｡ 依頼人は 神様だ｡
That's right, Shinpachi. The customer is always right.
なんでも 言うこと聞くんだぞ｡
おわっ…！
Listen to whatever he says.
ちょっ… これ どういうこと!?
何 言ってやがる！
Hey, what's going on?!
Don't you know?
勝った人間が ありがた～い仕事に
従事できるんだよ！
To the winner goes the spoils of this job. Be grateful.
(親父)感謝するんだな｡
いや そうじゃなくて…｡
No, it's not that...
えっ？ えぇっ!?
(２人)いってらっしゃ～い！
Have fun!
(隊士たち)でや～～っ!!
♪♪～
[To the Silver-haired Samurai:
Show your face at Shinsengumi Headquarters, you bastard!
We're the police! Signed, Shinsengumi]
(隊士)どこだ～!? 銀髪の侍!!
(隊士)とっとと 出てきやがれ～!!
Where are you, silver-haired samurai?!
Come on out!
(親父)ほら ここだ｡
Over here!
いや なんていうかさ…
どうにも 釈然としねえんだけど｡
[Shuei Construction]
Say, I really can't get into this.
文句ばっか言うな｡
とっとと現場へ 荷物 運ぶぞ｡
Quit bitching! Haul these supplies to the site.
いたぞ！ 銀髪の侍だ!!
There's the silver-haired samurai!
(隊士)銀髪の侍 そこか!!
There you are, silver-haired samurai!
こ… これは…!?
銀ｼｬﾘと 侍!?
Th-This is...
A samurai eating white rice?!
Seconds!
(侍)おかわり｡
(３人)ﾃﾒｴに食わす米なんてねえ!!
There's no rice for samurai like you!
見つけた～！ 銀髪の侍だ!!
Found him! It's the silver-haired samurai!
ここか！ 銀髪の侍!!
Gotcha! Silver-haired samurai!
こ… これは…!?
散髪の侍!?
H-He's...
...a samurai getting a haircut?!
(店員)本日は どのように？
(侍)う～ん すいといて｡
How would you like it cut?
Just trim it.
(３人)いっそ ﾊｹﾞにしろよ!!
Just shave it all off!
(親父)ちゃっちゃと働け！
仕事は 山ほどあんだからよ～｡
Just get with it. There's a mountain of work to be done.
わかってねえな｡
人を使うってのはよ➡
You don't get it, do you?
When you employ people, you have to inspire them, make them soar. You know?
相手 舞い上がらせて
なんぼだって 知ってっか？
(親父)はいはい｡
舞い上がって落ちねえように➡
Fine, soar as high as you like and make sure you don't fall. Here.
気いつけな｡ ほらよ！
(土方)なんだと～!?
What?!
手当たりしだいに ｶﾞｻ入れして
江戸中に➡
They've put signs up all over Edo and now the whole town knows about Kondo's loss?
近藤さんが 負けたってことを
貼り紙して回ってるだ～!?
えぇ｡ そりゃもう
ﾊﾃﾞに やりまくってますぜ｡
Yeah, they're going hog wild posting it up.
その割には 成果は
さっぱりみたいですけど｡
And for all that, they haven't gotten any results.
(土方)あの ﾊﾞｶ野郎どもが…！
Those morons!
ﾃﾒｴらで 局長が負けたこと
言いふらして どうすんだ！
What's the sense in telling the whole world your chief lost a duel?
(沖田)どうしやす？
このまま ほっときゃ➡
What do you want to do?
If we don't do anything, the whole town will be inconvenienced and the reputation of the Shinsengumi will be in the mud.
町中に 迷惑が かかるうえに
真選組の評判 がた落ちですぜ｡
Let's go, Sogo.
いくぞ 総悟｡
…って どこへ行くんですかい？
Go where?
What? Kill him?
(沖田)なんですって？ 斬る!?
(土方)あぁ 斬る｡
Yeah, I'm gonna kill 'em.
例の 銀髪の侍を？
あぁ｡
You talking about the silver-haired samurai?
Yeah, I'll finish him off before this mess gets any bigger.
これ以上 でけえことになる前に
ｵﾚが 始末する｡
土方さんは ふた言目には
斬る で困りまさあ｡
Every other word you utter is "kill."
古来暗殺で
大事を成した人は いませんぜ｡
The lessons of history teach us that nothing good comes from assassination.
(土方)暗殺じゃねえ｡
堂々と行って 斬ってくる｡
This isn't assassination.
I'll just walk right up to him and cut him down.
そこまでせんでも 適当に➡
No need to go that far.
Just haul in any old white-haired dude and the troops'll forget all about it!
銀髪頭の侍 見繕って
連れかえりゃ➡
隊士たちも 納得しますぜ｡
(沖田)これなんて どうです？
How about this one?
ほら ちゃんと 木刀持ちな｡
Here, hold this wooden sword, wouldja?
(土方)じいさん その木刀で
ｿｲﾂの頭 かち割ってくれ｡
Pops, swing this wooden sword a few times and beat this guy's head in.
土方さん ﾊﾟｯと見は冴えないですが
ﾒｶﾞﾈ取ったら…➡
At first glance he's not very imposing, but take off his glases...
ほら 武蔵じゃん｡
(土方)なに そのﾑﾀﾞなかっこよさ！
and..."wow" Hey look! It's Musashi!
What's the point of drawing him looking cool?!
ﾏｼﾞで やる気ですかい？
You really want to kill that dude?
銀髪って情報しか
こっちには ないってのに｡
All we know is that he's got white hair.
近藤さん 負かすからには
ただ者じゃねえ｡
He can't be just anyone if he beat Kondo.
見れば すぐ わかるさ｡
I'll know who he is when I see him.
[TEL]
(土方)あぁ ｵﾚだ｡
Yeah, it's me.
…そうか｡ わかった｡
(沖田)見つかったんですかい？
Really? Got it.
Found him?
山崎が それらしいﾔﾂを
見つけたらしい｡
Yamazaki found someone who seems to be him.
とにかく行くぞ｡
Let's go.
This is the place.
(土方)ここか…｡
真選組だ！ 御用改めである!!
Shinsengumi! We have government business!
(侍)何か ご用ですか？
What is your business?
(土方)こりゃあ…｡
This is...
(山崎)ｶﾂｶﾂの侍…｡
(沖田)おぉ｡
...a really...poor samurai?!
The only part that's right is "samurai"!
｢ﾂ｣しか合ってねえじゃねえか！
山崎 ﾃﾒｴ！ 今すぐ切腹しろ ｺﾗｧ!!
Commit seppuku this minute!
(山崎の叫び声)
銀髪の侍か…｡
いったい どこにいるんですかね｡
A silver-haired samurai.
I wonder where he could be?
(親父)気合い入れろ！ ｶﾅﾂﾞﾁは
もっと 魂 込めて 打つんだよ｡
You dirtbag! Put your soul into that hammer!
ｵﾒｴの頭にだったら 魂 込めて➡
If this was your head, I'd put my soul into the hammer, baldy.
打ち込んでやるよ ﾊｹﾞ｡
んだと この野郎！
Shut up, you jerk!
(親父)ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞの銀髪ﾊﾟｰﾏの分際で
偉そうなこと言うな！
Don't talk like you know it all, damned wavy-silver-haired mophead!
(沖田)見つかりませんねぇ｡
Can't find him. I think you don't have enough clues yet.
やっぱり 手がかりが
少なすぎるんじゃないんですか？
もう帰りませんか？
『ﾚﾃﾞｨｽ４』 始まっちゃいますよ｡
Why don't we go back? "Ladies 4" is gonna start.
(土方)いつから鞍替えしたんだ？
When'd they switch? There's been a drama rerun at four.
たしか ４時からは
ﾄﾞﾗﾏの再放送だろうが｡
え… そうでしたっけか？
Oh, really?
いやぁ あのﾄﾞﾗﾏ
ﾊｯﾋﾟｰｴﾝﾄﾞらしいから…｡
But hey, that drama's supposed to have a happy ending.
(土方)ｵﾒｴだって
そうなんだろうが｡
(沖田)ん？
You too, huh?
ﾍﾗﾍﾗ笑ってたって
内心 穏やかじゃねえんだろ｡
You laugh on the outside, but you're crying on the inside, huh?
さぁ どうでしょう｡
I wonder.
(土方)忘れたわけじゃあるまい｡
武州の田舎で➡
You haven't forgotten, have you?
Back in the old samurai country, the one who pulled us out of that humdrum life
くすぶってた ｵﾚたちを
引き上げてくれたのは➡
was none other than Kondo.
他でもねえ 近藤さんだ｡
(土方)ｵﾚたち 真選組が
今 こうして➡
We, the Shinsengumi, can walk around town with our heads held high
胸張って 町を歩けんのは
あの人のおかげなんだ｡
because of that man.
(土方)ｵﾚたちは あの人に
ついていく って決めたんだ｡
We decided to follow him.
そうだろ？ 総悟｡
Isn't that right, Sogo?
ほら いけ ｻﾄﾞ丸３号｡
ﾀｰｹﾞｯﾄは ｱｲﾂのｹﾂだ！
So, Sadomaru III. The target is the butt.
ﾃﾒｴ 聞いてんのか ｺﾗ！
Hey, are you listening?!
ﾁｯ｡
おい 兄ちゃん 危ないよ｡
Dammit!
Hey, watch it, bro.
ん？ …うわぉっ！
(土方)危ねえだろうが！
だから 危ねえっつったろ｡
H-Hey, that's dangerous!
I said, watch it.
Say it with more emotion then! Got it?
もっと ﾃﾝｼｮﾝ上げて言えや！
わかるか！
うるせえなぁ｡
Oh, shut your hole.
Like I'm supposed to listen to a stranger coach me on dramatic delivery!
他人から ﾃﾝｼｮﾝのﾀﾞﾒ出しまで
される覚えはねえよ｡
あぁっ！
(土方)ﾃﾒｴは 池田屋のときの…！
It's... you! The guy from that time at Ikedaya...
ん？
♪♪～
It's... you! The guy from that time at Ikedaya...
(土方)ﾃﾒｴは 池田屋のときの…！
ん？
Oh yeah, I forgot...
(土方)そうか…
そういや ﾃﾒｴも 銀髪だったな｡
you've got silver hair.
え～と… ｷﾐ 誰？
Umm, who are you?
…あぁ もしかして 多串君か？
Is that you, Ogushi? Man, you're looking so important.
あらら～
すっかり 立派になっちゃって｡
なに？ まだ あの金魚
でかくなってんの？
What's up? Your pet gold fish ever get any bigger?
Hey, Gin! Hurry up, will ya!
(親父)お～い 銀さん！
早く こっち頼むって！
Be right up!  'scuse me, Ogushi.  Gotta get back to work.
はいよ｡
じゃ 多串君 ｵﾚ 仕事だから｡
行っちゃいましたよ｡
どうしやす？ 多串君｡
He took off!
Whatcha gonna do about it, Ogushi?
誰が 多串君だ！
Who you callin' Ogushi?
(土方)あの野郎 わずか３～４週で
人のこと 忘れやがって｡
That jerk! He forgets me after just three or four episodes!
(沖田)いや
普通 忘れると思いやすぜ｡
Well, I think most would.
Sogo, lend me your sword.
総悟 ちょっと 刀 貸せ｡
まったくよ～｡
Dammit...
こんなﾊｹﾞと １日 一緒に
仕事なんかしてたら➡
If I have to work all day with this baldy, I'll go bald!
こっちまで ﾊｹﾞにならぁ｡
Sheesh! If help weren't so hard to find, I'd never have gone to your place!
ﾁｯ… 人手不足じゃなかったら➡
ﾃﾒｴんとこなんかに
頼まねえのによ｡
はぁ… そこ ちゃんとやっとけよ｡
Don't screw that up, y'hear?
ｵﾒｴもな ﾊｹﾞ｡
Same to you, baldy.
(土方)爆弾処理の次は
屋根の修理か？
First bomb disposal, now roof repair?
節操のねえ野郎だ｡
いったい何がしてえんだ？ ﾃﾒｴは｡
You've got no self-respect at all, do you?
What's your story anyway?
爆弾？
Bomb?
♪♪～
お前 あんときの…｡
You were there too, huh?
やっと思い出したか｡
Finally remembered, eh?
(土方)あんなﾑﾁｬするﾔﾂは
真選組にもいないんでね｡
There's no one even in the Shinsengumi who's that crazy.
(爆発音)
(土方)近藤さんを負かすﾔﾂが
いるなんざ 信じられなかったが➡
I thought Kondo was invincible
but if it's you, it's a little more believable.
ﾃﾒｴなら ありえない話でもねえ｡
近藤さん？
Kondo?
女 取り合った仲なんだろ？
You two fought over a woman, remember?
Is she worth it?
(土方)そんなに いい女なのか？
ｵﾚにも紹介してくれよ｡
Introduce me to her, will ya?
Hey...the tip...!
((あれ～ 先っちょがぁ～!!))
You're friends with gorilla-butt?
お前 あのｺﾞﾘﾗの知り合いかよ!?
にしても 何のﾏﾈだ？ こりゃ｡
…はっ！
What are you coming after me for?
でやっ！
ぐわっ！
がっ！ たっ！ とっ!!
What's the big idea?!
何しやがんだ ﾃﾒｴ!!
(土方)ｺﾞﾘﾗだろうがなぁ➡
He may be a gorilla, but to us, he's our beloved general!
ｵﾚたちにとっちゃ
大事な大将なんだよ｡
ｺｲﾂ１本で 一緒に
真選組を作り上げてきた➡
He built the Shinsengumi up from nothing with just one sword.
ｵﾚの戦友なんだよ｡
He's my brother-in-arms!
(土方)誰にも
ｵﾚたちの真選組は 汚させねえ｡
I won't let anyone shame our unit...
and who so ever crosses that line, my blade...
その道を
遮るものがあるならば…➡
...shall taste his blood!
ｺｲﾂで たたき斬るのみだ!!
…はっ｡
It's time for Ladies 4!
(神楽)『ﾚﾃﾞｨｽ４』の時間ｱﾙよ｡
♪♪(ﾚﾃﾞｨｽ４のﾃｰﾏｿﾝｸﾞ)
刃物を…
ﾌﾟﾗﾌﾟﾗ 振り回すんじゃねえ!!
Quit...
...swinging that sword around!
(土方)ぐわっ…！
Nuohh!
♪♪～
ぐわぁっ！
ん… なんだ？
Huh? What's going on?
おい 銀さん！ ﾃﾒｴ 遊んでたら
ｷﾞｬﾗ 払わねえぞ！
Hey, Gin! You don't get paid if you're just playing around!
Shut up, baldy! Call the police! The police!
うるせえよ ﾊｹﾞ！
警察 呼べ！ 警察!!
ｵﾚが 警察だよ｡
I am the police.
あ… そうだったな｡
世も末だな おい｡
Huh? Oh yeah. Man, this world is coming to an end.
(土方)ﾌﾌ… そうだな｡
Heh, you're so right.
I can't figure this guy out.
《なんだか 読めねえ野郎だな》
ｲﾃﾃ…｡
《土方:近藤さんのときは➡
I heard he used a dirty trick against Kondo,
汚え手 使ったって聞いたが
そんな素振りも見せねえ｡
but he's not doing anything like that now.
それどころか 貸した刀さえ
使おうとしやがらねえとは…｡
Far from it... he's not even defending himself with the sword I gave him.
まさか ｺｲﾂ… ﾃﾒｴが
命 狙われてるにもかかわらず➡
Could it be that, even though his life's in danger... he's trying to be chivalrous?
ｵﾚを 気遣ってるのか？》
ｸｯ…！
Damn!
Draw that sword!
(土方)抜け！ やる気のねえﾃﾒｴ
斬ったところで➡
Killing a guy who won't fight back'll leave a bad taste in my mouth!
寝覚めが悪いんだよ！
早く抜け!!
Hurry up! Draw!
♪♪～
ﾌﾝ いよいよ くるかよ｡
All right, he's finally getting down to business.
(土方)命のやりとりといこうや!!
Your life or mine!
うらぁ～っ!!
殺った!! …はっ！
Got him!
なにっ!?
What?!
《かわされた!? 斬られる！》
Parried! He got me.
(金属音)
は～い 終了｡
Okay, fight's over.
ｲﾃﾃﾃ…｡
おい ﾊｹﾞ！
ｵﾚ ちょっと 病院 行ってくるわ｡
Hey, baldy! I'm gonna take some sick leave!
(土方)待て！
Hold it!
You took mercy on me?
ﾃﾒｴ… 情けでもかけたつもりか？
情けだぁ？ そんなもん
お前に かけるくらいなら➡
Mercy?
If I had any of that, I'd put it on my rice and eat it.
ご飯に かけるわ｡
喧嘩ってのはよぉ
何か守るためにやるもんだろうが｡
You fight when you have something to protect.
お前が
真選組 守ろうとしたようによ｡
Like you tried to protect the Shinsengumi.
Protect?
守るって…
お前は 何 守ったってんだ？
Then what did you protect?
ｵﾚの ﾙｰﾙだ｡
My own rules.
じゃあな｡
See ya.
♪♪～
(沖田)ﾌﾌ… おもしれえ人だ｡
That guy's a trip.
ｵﾚも 一戦 交えたくなりましたぜ｡
Wouldn't mind crossing swords with him myself.
(近藤)やめとけ｡
お前でも ｷﾂｲぞ？ 総悟｡
Forget it. Even you would have a tough time of it, Sogo.
ｱｲﾂは 目の前で
刃を合わせていても➡
He may point his blade at you,
全然 別のところで
勝手に闘ってるような男なんだよ｡
but he's fighting on some other plane.
(近藤)勝ちも負けも
浄も不浄も超えたところでな｡
It's beyond winning and losing for him, beyond right and wrong.
Sorry, Kondo. He beat me, too.
悪い 近藤さん…
ｵﾚも 負けちまったよ｡
♪♪～
[Up next: Please Teach Us, Ginpachi Sensei]
銀八先生 このあと すぐ｡
Ginpachi Sensei after these messages!
[Preview]
What is this?!
Kagura, if you're gonna pick up strays, pick up something we recognize the name of!
Huh? You're gonna keep it? No way!
Mom'll never allow it!
The next episode:
"Eat Something Sour When You're Tired"
[Prince Baka... Hata from Midland Star is back again.]
[And this guy with dilated pupils, who was ordered to find a unique pet?]
[Please Teach Us, Ginpachi Sensei]
Please teach us, Ginpachi Sensei!
Here's a question from "Go back to Ehime, Onishi."
"There's something I've been wondering about..."
"What," you ask?
Well, Shinpachi said...
"The anti-foreigner faction tried to drive out the Amanto when they invaded twenty years ago."
"In other words, Gin and Katsura must be way past their thirties now, right?"
Fine. Now listen up, because this will be on the test.
The Joi War didn't end in just one year or so.
When the Amanto came to Earth twenty years ago, Gin was still a little kid with no hair on his privates.
The government got scared and were forced to open the country to the Amanto.
And throughout the land, samurai fought back but got their asses kicked.
At that point, Gin's pubic hair began to grow.
Eventually, the Amanto infiltrated even the government and had their way.
And it is during this time that Gin began his romp.
え～ ｢愛媛に帰れ 大西さん｣
からの質問｡
No, I don't mean like that.
｢不思議に
思っていることがあります｡
And that basically sums up the several decades of the samurai struggle known as
何かって ｱﾝﾀ そりゃ
新八君が言ってましたよね？
攘夷とは 20年前の
天人襲来のときに起きた➡
the "Anti-Foreigner War."
Gin and the others got involved during the latter part of this period.
宇宙人を
排そうとする思想… って｡
In conclusion, Onishi, you go out and stand in the hallway and think about that.
つまり 銀さんとか桂さんとかって
どう少なく見積もっても➡
もう 三十路越えてるっつうことに
なるんですよね｣
大丈夫だ｡
え～ ここ ﾃｽﾄに出るから
よく聞いとくように｡
攘夷戦争ってのは これ➡
１年やそこらで
終わったものじゃございません｡
20年前 天人が
地球にやってきたときは➡
銀さんは
まだ 毛も生えてないｶﾞｷです｡
天人にﾋﾞﾋﾞった幕府は
開国してしまい➡
各地で 侍たちが蜂起しますが
ﾎﾞｺﾎﾞｺに やられてしまいます｡
ちなみに 銀さんは➡
この頃くらいから
毛が生え出します｡
やがて 天人が
幕府にまで潜り込んで➡
好き勝手やるようになった頃から
銀さんが暴れ出します｡
いやぁ
そういう意味じゃなくて…｡
はい というように➡
これら10数年に亘る
侍の悪あがきを総称して➡
攘夷戦争というわけです｡
銀さんたちは このうち
後半で活躍した連中なわけですね｡
ということで 大西
お前 廊下に立ってなさい｡